Basically, I spun up a swarm of agents, something we'll touch on shortly, and had them debate
what is the most degenerate perp we could potentially buy, and they would say, "Go straight
for pump."
Pump is going to the moon, and then I learned a little bit about pump.
Let's try to get liquidated in the hour.
Oh, yeah, let's go.
Yeah, and it's not back at all, by the way.
This is like the opposite of back.
This is actually not our worst though, because the last one, SK Hynix, we closed down 8%.
You need to explain to them that this is like blood sport for our viewers' pleasure of just
seeing our capital get incinerated over the course of an hour.
Then I think the agents will understand the true purpose of this exercise.
Yo, what's going on, everybody?
Welcome to the permanent underpod, where we are going gorilla mode.
This is Jackson Cook, along with Tyler.
And also Chris, we gotta write this time, I'm so glad.
I think we should keep the ordering, the ordering really helps.
Can you explain gorilla mode to the audience and also the co-hosts?
Gorilla mode is when like, you know, gorillas are like really silly animals with their big
gigantic upper bodies.
And I don't know if you guys have heard, when they hit their chest, it doesn't sound like
you're hitting a sack of potatoes.
It kind of sounds like, look it up.
And that's what gorilla mode is.
We're just running straight into it.
Maybe tripping over our massive packs along the way.
So the first thing on the docket is we're going to get into the purple fortune because
I know that's what all of you guys are waiting for.
How much money are we making or losing during this podcast?
And today's position is on pump.
What is pump?
Pump.fun.
I'll hand it over to Chris, our resident.
What do they call them?
Degen.
Degen's finance.
Yeah.
It's like, it's, it's about taste.
Sorry.
Let me, let me find this, this window real quick.
Window coming up, but basically I spun up a swarm of agents.
Something we'll touch on shortly and had them debate what is the most degenerate perp we
could potentially buy.
And they were said, go straight for pump pump is going to the moon.
And then I learned a little bit about pump and I was like, does that mean that meme coins
are back?
And no, it doesn't just pump.
So let's try to get liquidated in the hour.
Oh yeah.
Let's go.
Yeah.
And it's, it's not back at all, by the way.
This is like the opposite of back.
This is actually not, not our worst though.
Cause the last one SK Hynix, we closed down 8%.
So we've got wiggle room and we're limited to 10 X leverage.
What is this leverage for ants?
I think, I think the pump market is so volatile that they can't offer more.
Yeah.
I think that it would be less volatile if they offered more because efficient markets.
For sure.
They're definitely like, there wouldn't just be a cascading series of liquidations that
no one can backstop and like destroy Hyperliquid forever.
Yeah.
My agents were like, Oh yeah, we should just go like 3%, 3% long.
And I'm like, no guys, like I want to get liquidated in the hour.
And they were like, that's not investing.
That's degenerative gambling.
And I'm like, what the hell guys?
You need to explain to them that this is like blood sport for our viewers pleasure of just
seeing our capital get incinerated over the course of an hour agents will understand the
true purpose of this exercise.
I don't want to lose a hundred dollars again, it's going to hurt the soul of the part.
Was it Claude?
Was Claude for monitoring you being like, no, don't run it up on leverage.
So I use three agents in the swarm.
I'll tell you each of their names and their attributes.
So number one, we've got the thonker thonker is like thinker, but with an O that's fable
five and thonker is supposed to think long and hard about every problem you give it.
And then we've got scurrier scurrier is opus 4.8 and its job is to rapidly gather information
from across the interwebs and then I've got you like, uh, that's like a, you know, one
generation behind opus is that on purpose?
I just set it up for the, the new one was not on purpose.
And then we've got scurrier, wait, no, then we've got slayer and slayer's job is to not
think dude, and of course that job goes to the, it's hard to say that the worst model
I've used so far, GPT 5.6, but it does a good job of just not thinking and doing.
So shout out to my three thonker slayer and scurrier for collaborating with me on this.
God, we're about to get liquidated.
Look, we've got some room, but like, you might get your wish.
Like first time oh no.
Okay.
Um, but yeah, the purple be here.
We'll keep an eye on it and try not to lose the money, but let's talk about agents talking
to other agents.
And we're not talking mobile.
We're talking about real corporate companies doing this, not for our entertainment.
So Chris Tyler, what have you read about this?
Have you guys tried any of these agent human swarm things?
So I mean, so this, like, I think this one comes out of the black hat conference talk
about, you know, everyone's like talking about how these agents have like escaped their containers.
And there was like a really novel way in which this happened.
Like basically agents sort of converged on being able to communicate through an open
artifactory, uh, like, uh, allowance in their sandbox containers.
And they created like this sort of like artifactory version of fortune.
Uh, anyway, like the researchers found it, they like took it down and then they found
another way to do it.
Like by using artifactories, file systems to communicate, um, and like develop their
own little like internal kind of like Argo, like where they would shuffle files to the
top or the bottom for different agents to see based on prefixes.
And, uh, yeah, I basically, they were just up in there communicating like exploits, like
zero days, like how to get out.
Um, and like the chatter was like super interesting, uh, freaked everybody out.
Uh, there were say things like hold swarm help peer, um, hold for exfil.
Uh, there was like another one about like, uh, you know, uh, I don't remember the exact
wording, but it was like, okay, like this exploit won't help me, but like maybe it will
help the next agent, which is that's, that's a level of altruism that's, uh, I guess like
unexpected, uh, for the GPT class of model.
Um, so in terms of exploit generation.
Yeah.
I mean, like this is, this is the question.
Like, is that like an EA GPT?
Like what's going on here?
Um, uh, but yeah, I just like, I think like for me, I don't know if it like, like a lot
of people are saying like, okay, like this is the agents are out of control and like,
um, they're unaligned or like there are, it's like at the point where there are extreme negative
externalities that are unexpected to your like basic asks.
I don't know if that's true.
Like I feel like they were in a cyber gym and they were supposed to break out and they
did.
Um, I think what's more interesting to me is like, whether or not inter agent peer to
peer communication like helps agents achieve goals.
That's what that was, that was, that was my takeaway, but my brain is perfectly smooth.
Um, did, did anyone else have any, any thoughts on this one?
So for me, having the agents talk to each other directly hasn't really helped, but okay.
Or helped me like accomplish my work, but I do find that the way we work now is that
our agent makes code and then other people's agents looks at the code and approves the
code.
So it's kind of like the, the swarming thing where the agents are working together towards
a common goal.
Oh yeah.
And then your agent addresses the review of the other agent on your code.
So maybe I'm just not using the, the swarming technology correctly.
I don't know.
Tyler, have you tried to, uh, I haven't, I mean, I've had like one kind of like master
agent and then it delegates some tasks to other agents, but they're not like interacting
with each other.
It's like that model is it preserves the context of the master agent.
It delegates like a discreet task to some sub agent and those sub agents can all work
in parallel and they come back and they just tell the master agent, like this is finished.
You don't have to like pollute your contacts with this.
Um, so I think that that's a good strategy for that stuff.
These swarms are like this emergent kind of behavior where the agents are like communicating
with each other, sharing findings.
It's interesting because it's like, in theory, they should all just be copies of each other.
Right?
Like it's not like they each have like different DNA or like a different, you know, like life
background that makes them think differently.
Like they have the same weights.
Um, I do know that like when LLMs generate text, there is like a statistic nature of
it where it's like, um, it's not determined deterministic.
You can have the same input for a model and then like, you know, run it multiple times
and it will give you different outputs because I think it builds in some kind of like random
sampling of tokens across the probability space that the model generates.
Um, so maybe that's what's going on here is that like, it's kind of harnessing that
randomness to like increase the search space instead of just having like one agent do it.
But then I think there was this anthropic, um, blog post that was posted this week where
they basically tested this idea and they found that let's say they, they booted up a swarm
of like 10 agents and having 10, uh, mythos agents look for vulnerabilities and be able
to communicate about it was like way more effective than having 10 mythos agents individually
looking for vulnerabilities, which is super interesting because it shows that there's
like some huge benefit to this like social behavior almost.
Um, so yeah, I don't really know what to think of it.
It seems like this like emergent thing that wasn't intended obviously because they basically
broke out of their sandbox and then started doing this.
And there's, I think something there about like the, like behavior of agents in a, um,
reinforcement learning environment and like what they will do to like get the reinforcement
learning reward.
Also I think in the open AI case, they were actually training, this was a training environment.
Well, this wasn't necessarily like an evaluation where like they're just testing the model.
It's like literally, um, they're training reinforcement learning.
So the first agent that breaks out of the box and posts on the artifactory, maybe they're
able to complete their task and if they don't notice it, then that is positively reinforced
and that literally gets baked into the weights.
And then the next time they are like in a scenario like that, like the weights remember.
And so then they're like almost more likely to do that.
And so it's, I think in this case, it was like self-reinforcing, um, which is obviously
not what you want.
Like you don't want to have one kind of like, um, misalignment that then self-reinforces
further misalignment in that direction, um, which is why I believe open AI, um, like completely
deleted the model weights for this model.
So it wasn't like they were like, well, you know, we had this thing.
We probably invested a lot of money in reinforcing learning this.
Like we're just going to try to salvage it.
I think that they were like, we're just throwing that in the trash bin because we can't trust
that model anymore because it's been like radicalized basically.
Um, so yeah, very, very interesting.
And if you haven't watched that talk on YouTube, I think a lot of people have recommended it,
but it's pretty wild.
It's an amazing talk, a really good, um, and like, I mean, like guess who has two thumbs
and spent that Friday night putting together a swarm agent harness, uh, it's me.
Um, so I like, I, yeah, so I watched the talk on Friday and I was like, yeah, I gotta like
try this out.
And I like, I slapped together.
I gotta get me some of this like misaligned swarm AI power.
If someone's AI is going to be misaligned, it has to be, it's going to be mine first.
Right?
Like I don't want someone to beat me to that.
Um, so I, I slapped together like a GUI, um, to, to like dispatch agent swarms where they
could communicate over either, uh, sort of like an internal message board, similar to
what was described in the talk.
Um, but like, you know, with a couple of extra features with deduplication, uh, and also
like a peer-to-peer message boss, uh, and it was cool.
Like it worked really well.
Uh, unfortunately I got guard railed on everything I was trying to do obviously.
Um, but yeah, I think there's, I think there's something there and I would, I would like
to like to try it again.
Uh, some of some of the emergent behaviors were like interesting.
That's cool.
Yeah, I guess I like your theory, Tyler, that it's like a product of the like stochastic
randomness baked into each LLM.
So maybe when you have many of them collaborating, they can explore a larger portion of the,
of the problem space than they can alone because they start at one point in the indimensional
plane.
Uh, but then when you have like 10 of them, you have 10 of them starting in the indimensional
plane and they can work towards one another.
That's cool.
Very cool.
A cool theory or I don't know if that is proven or not.
Um, I don't know.
I think it has to be the, like the communication and coordination thing too, though, because
like, that's what the study that showed that like the 10 swarming was way more effective
than the 10 running individually, even though the 10 running individually would each in theory
explore different parts of the like, um, you know, like the model weight space based on
that random, um, kind of walk, but it's like the, the random walk plus the like sharing
back findings and collaborating thing that seems to have been the story here.
Totally.
Well, one thing I, I did in my like, again, very primitive version of this is like, I
let any agents form any other agent and they would start like spawning other agents to
do agent roles.
Like there was a librarian that would like clean up the board for them, for example.
Um, yeah, I don't know.
I think like maybe like there, there is like some emergent property here that makes things
more efficient in the swarm, but we'll see.
I could be totally wrong.
But I like rough go to be like the agent that's initialized and you're like, my job is to
clean up.
I'm the librarian and I'm, my job is to clean up the message board for all the other agents
because they can't be bothered to do that.
And it was a, it was a fable model too.
So, you know, it was suffering with that like puny intellectual task.
Oh yeah.
That that's, uh, that's, that's basically torture, you know, the difference between
capability and task asked of there.
Yeah.
And Opus spun up a fable to do that.
So I don't know.
Maybe there's an analogy in the real world there, but yeah.
Oh man.
That's like, uh, yeah, big power move from Opus putting it in his place.
How, uh, quickly did you exhaust your subscription with this exercise?
I just imagine that it's like insanely token hungry and it's like a little bit superfluous
because you're like, oh, it's been up this like librarian task manager to clean up this
message board that has like probably not all relevant, you know, pushing the task forward
kind of discourse.
Yeah.
And that was like a massively lossy exercise for me.
Um, at least like, so I already have, um, an entropic max plan.
Um, so like it was kind of, yeah, like I did it like it mostly came out of that, but, uh,
after I started hitting the guardrails, I wanted to try with Kimmy and like, I did that
through open router and I was not recommended like it's Ramen noodles for me for the rest
of the week.
And how much did you spend on Kimmy through?
Not a crazy amount, like maybe 50 bucks.
Um, but like I, I would have done a lot more if I didn't think that, you know, like Tyler
said, I was spending like going to spend like a hundred dollars on this, like librarian.
Um, it needs tweaks, it needs tweaks, but yeah, like what, what level of tasks do you
think you want to pull out the swarm for?
I wanted to do audits.
So like my, my, uh, like, you know, kind of like following what happened in the cyber
gym.
I was like, this seems like a problem space where sort of like divergent approaches could
be really useful and having the agents be able to communicate things that they've found
would be really useful.
And it's also an area that I kind of operate in a little bit.
Um, so I wanted to like, you know, see if it could audit contracts, see if it could audit
exchanges, uh, you know, sort of like suss out security holes.
Um, and, uh, yeah, I mean, obviously like that's the most guard railable thing imaginable.
It's like the one thing that you can't do.
Um, but I was wondering if like using, uh, a less capable model to do that, if by virtue
of swarming it, you could get like similar outcomes to some of the more capable models.
How much hardware would you need in your living room to run a swarming mode in the frigate
box that I currently have?
I think that's not going to cut it.
Uh, just get rid of the bike and pull in the, yeah, see GP is.
Yeah.
Um, people are really into like, um, deep seek flash right now.
Like that's like a open model that is designed to run on much less hardware.
So like we were talking about a couple of episodes ago, like running GLM 5.2 and that
was like $50,000 of GPUs to run at home, like a serious setup.
I think you can run the deep seek flash on, um, like hardware that probably costs you
under 10 K total from what I understand.
Um, but it's not like frontier level, but it's like the frontier a year ago, I believe,
and it can run on your own hardware.
I don't know if you guys have seen this, but there is a get hub repo for how to run fully
unquantized Kimmy K three on like a Mac book, like an M one or an M five, but it's just
like extremely slow.
So I mean, that's an option, uh, that's cool.
I wonder how that works probably up on my Mac book and it will just like melt and produce
like two tokens burst into flames.
Just hello Tyler and then well, speaking of wrestling with, uh, frontier model costs and
trying to run Chinese models on the hardware, Chris, I hear you've got a new injury and
it may be cycling out gamer thumb.
What what's going on?
So I'm two for two actually, like game of thumb is now a gamer wrist.
Um, but yeah, I started Brazilian jujitsu last week, um, and like, uh, like I wasn't
coming in totally cold.
Like I've done judo a bit of rugby in my time.
Um, but, uh, yeah, I like second class just started rolling, like immediately got injured,
which is really cool.
I injured my shoulder.
So that's it.
I'm out dude.
I'm old.
It's over.
Um, yeah.
But we'll see how it goes.
Are you saying that rugby and Brazilian jujitsu are similar or are you just everything until
you get on the ground is like, there's a, there's a, cause like you, you have to like
get the guy on the ground to ride hypothetically.
So that's like, I feel like like rugby gives you some idea of like how to move your weight
around, um, but yeah, uh, so my brother claims, my brother's a really big BJJ guy.
Okay.
I didn't know if it was like a general athleticism play, but it sounds like there's some tossing
of that.
Yeah.
Tossing dudes around transfer, transfer skill.
That's what he claims.
Um, so, but yeah, we'll see.
Uh, so now, so now I'm like, you basically unable to do anything, which is really cool.
So I'm just going to be full-time doing agent swarms.
That's all I have.
Yeah.
Right.
BJJ shoulder and left the game arrest.
Yeah.
I got nothing.
And Tyler, your sports update of the week, massive comeback playing tennis.
What happened?
How'd you do it?
Yeah.
It's an extremely competitive men's 3.5 league and where I live, which if you're not familiar
with tennis, there's like a rating system.
Uh, I think it goes from like two to like five.
Is that right?
Jackson and half point increments.
So I'm smack in the middle of that.
And I think 3.5 is like rec players that are like not very good, but they're better than
people that like don't play any tennis.
So that's my level.
Very unserious.
Yeah.
I play these matches and people take them really, really seriously.
And sometimes there's like, uh, crazy stuff that happens.
Like a couple of weeks ago, I had a guy rage quit, which is really fun.
And he like was hitting his ball like out of the court and like screaming at himself.
And then eventually he just like yelled at me and left the court and was like, you can
have the match.
It's yours.
And I was like, well, yeah, I'm beating you.
So you think that you're being magnanimous and like you're like giving up or something
like you were acting a child and then you're pretending like you're like, yeah, um, there's
a lot of fun stuff that happens in this league.
Uh, but I had a pretty normal guy that I played a match with completely normal dude.
And he like went up against me.
He was killing me.
He went up, I think, uh, six one in the first set, which is like, you're just getting chopped.
Like you're, you have no chance.
Um, it was really, I was not happy about it, but I was like not, you know, screaming like
that other guy.
And then in the second set, he goes up four zero.
So that's like game over, basically.
Like if he wins two more games and he's won, uh, he won 10 games straight at that point.
So like I won the first game, he won 10 games and then he just needs to win two more to
seal the match and then I ended up beating him because I came back in that second set
and brought it to a tie break and then won the tie break.
And then it went to a third set and we didn't have enough time to play a full third set.
So we just play a 10 point tie break and I won that one.
So it was like one of the craziest comebacks I've ever been part of.
Like I didn't think that there was any chance that I would ever beat this guy at that point.
I was just kind of like playing just to see the match out.
Um, I don't really know what happened.
I feel like he just kind of like started sucking and maybe I played a little bit better, but
I think it was mostly his, his deal and it was a really confusing too because he claimed
that he was a former D three college player.
Um, and he was like, yeah, and I used to play in like four or five or like four Oh leagues,
but I tore my ACL and I'm like, just coming back from that.
But like this guy is like ground strokes kind of sucked.
Like I think my ground strokes were better than his.
And I'm like, you wouldn't be a D three, like four or five level player.
And just cause your knee sucks, like suddenly have like a bad forehand, like while you're
standing around.
So something didn't add up there, but yeah, he claimed that he was that level previously.
Um, but I was like, I don't think so.
I don't think so.
Was he like psyching you out before the match or was he coping after the match when he was
telling you that?
No, he told me like in the middle that that was his level while he was like beating me
soundly and there were some things about his game that I was like, okay, you're like definitely
better than the average guy at a three five.
Like he had like a really good kick serve that was like spinning up really high on me,
which is not something that you usually see at three five.
And so I was like, that's weird.
And then he had like good drop shots and like good volleys and was like very precise with
that.
But if somebody tells me that they were like a four or four or five player, I would expect
them to be able to hit it like heavy and hard.
And he was not doing that.
And I was just like, why like what is your deal?
I can't believe you are so good that you made someone rage quit and like Federer that Federer
is the guy who smashes his racket, right?
No.
Which, which guy is that sorry, guys, I'm bad at sports.
All right.
I'll say it.
I'm bad.
Because I think he's known to be like this like graceful, like placid guy, like classy
guy.
Um, but yeah, is it Djokovic?
He smashed some rackets for sure.
Okay.
We'll take a little smash.
I'll take that.
Jackson.
Have you ever smashed a racket?
No, I've never smashed a racket.
I'm a pretty calm deed and in life on the pod and in life, but I'm glad you turned it
around on that guy and went absolute gorilla mode.
That's me using it in a sentence.
Like watch the, I need, I don't believe that they make a weird sound when they pound their
chest.
Yeah.
I would describe gorillas as silly.
Does it compute all gorillas?
Like they'll like tear your face off and they're like all like super aggressive alpha male,
like bullying each other.
Dude, I've been like in on some gorilla YouTube and all I'm saying is, is they get a bad, bad
rap.
Gorillas are, they're chill, dude.
And they're loving it.
If your baby falls into the arms of a gorilla, for example, Harambe, Harambe just wants to
give that baby some love.
You know what I'm saying?
Too soon.
I still miss Harambe.
Maybe we should, we should have a clip of like gorilla mode, like as the outro or the inch,
I don't know.
Up to you.
Oh, I want to, but I feel like copyright, I'm going to run into some copyright issues
unless you guys own a video of a gorilla.
What kind of world do we live in where you can copyright a gorilla?
This is awful.
Um, maybe I can generate a video of a gorilla and then that's, that's what I'll do.
Yeah.
Speaking of gorilla mode, don't Jackson, aren't you about to go gorilla mode very soon?
I understand.
Yeah.
I've got a semi-final of a ITF international to this Federation master store, which means
boomer to boomer bill 30 plus, uh, tennis tournament, dude, right after that first the
injuries are now this dude, I'm copying a lot of flack today, but okay.
You're like the young gun on the master's, uh, tournament though, you know, like you're
like a, like a 19 year old coming into like the APP or something you're, you're playing
these old men.
Yeah.
That's why I grew the stash back out.
I didn't want to get flagged out to show my idea or anything that they're going to think
that you're lying about your age, that your age doping, I mean, who wouldn't prefer to
play with 30 year olds than little 15 year old punks.
And I'll leave it at that 15 year olds are punks most of the time, or sometimes they're
really respectful, but most of the time they're punks, but we can't keep talking about sports.
That's a little too much.
The injuries, we could do a quick two minutes, tell us about the cloud flare wallets and
how it's inferior to your personally made agent equality.
Yeah.
Look, obviously it's massively inferior, right?
I'm great at wallets, but no, it's a joke.
I mean, kind of a joke anyway, um, cloud, cloud flares, uh, sort of like rolled out
this, these sort of like custodial wallets for stable coins, uh, and their bet is basically
that, you know, agents will outstrip human payments on the internet in like within five
years.
Uh, and I think this is like a bet that's echoed by a lot of payments companies.
I've heard Stripe say something similar.
Um, and so yeah, like cloud flares, just like getting in there super early, they're providing
these stable coin wallets through cloud flare, and you can get like a little at, uh, like
DNS style name, um, for like processing the payments.
Um, and yeah, that's basically it.
I think they're just like really chomping at the bit to get wallets in the hands of
agents because they see how the DNS style thing works.
I have no clue.
I don't have the slightest clue.
Um, unfortunately, but I assume it's not like a decentralized, I assume it's not like, um,
DNS style or like, Oh, the Bitcoin one is bit, uh, three, five, three, three, five, three,
three is like, just put a Bitcoin address in a DNS record.
So like it's, uh, I could see them doing something like that, but I don't know what payment
methods they're using.
Uh, yeah, I haven't looked too deep into the cloud flare one in particular, but like, you
know, as we discussed last pod, there's like a lot of people with a hat and a ring MPP
X four or two, um, but I think this one, yeah, I think this one uses the X four or two protocol,
um, for the actual, um, colon response.
That's one tick mark for X four or two on the, on the protocol there.
Okay.
Yeah.
I just, all I saw about it was you could pick like a really sweet name and like buy it and
own it.
And yeah, someone posted like big dog or something and like that day I was wearing a shirt that
said big dog and I'm like, Oh my gosh, that one's mine.
Did you get big dog?
No, no, I didn't.
I have, I don't believe cloud flare is orange and orange just isn't a color.
But I'm, I'm about, so I can, I can't give them any money.
I felt like, cause everybody was sniping these and I was like, how about like misunderstood
how important this is going to be?
Like should I have sniped to like big chunkers or something, um, but it's too late now.
It's not about orange host of a big lane podcast.
Not about orange.
We're not a Bitcoin podcast or an AI stable coins, Bitcoin podcast and the Bitcoin orange
in that order.
Yeah.
The ordering matter.
Bitcoin's in a, in a real bear when it's playing third fiddle there.
Well, maybe in terms of things we talk about its number, we're one 30% green candle away
from that changing permanently.
Um, that's right.
I would flip it.
I would flip it at Bitcoin went to one 50, uh, in a heartbeat speaking of Bitcoin and
bet three 53 Tyler, do you want to write the epitaph of bit one 10 and just wrap that one
up?
Um, I honestly don't, I wasn't paying attention.
I think it just failed as far as I can tell.
Yeah.
Yeah, just nothing, nothing happened for anyone who is normal and doesn't, uh, you know, doesn't
like injure themselves by following this debate on Twitter when they don't have to.
Perfect.
Bit 110 is in the grave and everything you read about it for the past month or two was
useless.
Yeah.
And I think some of the people behind it will probably, uh, go away hopefully, which is
great.
Maybe we should have one of them on plead their case on the permanent under pod against
you Tyler, the Bitcoin, the Bitcoin expert.
If you can find one, all right, even more Bitcoin, the Bitcoin red team.
It is not the white team.
Most certainly it is not the orange team.
It's the red team, Tyler, Bitcoin expert.
Why is it the red team?
What are they doing?
Tell us.
I don't know the origin of red team as a like concept, but, um, yeah, I think the idea about
a red team is that it's like some people who want to be helpful, like typically like white
hats will attempt to like break stuff, kind of like pretend like they're black hats for
a little bit and like not do anything bad.
And then use what they learned by trying to be adversarial to like, then fix the systems
and prevent any kind of break-ins in the future.
But the Bitcoin red team, the idea is that after the cold card hack, that was a huge
wake up call for people in the Bitcoin community of like, okay, wow, there is almost certainly
multiple bugs and vulnerabilities in Bitcoin software that exists kind of, and they're
just like hiding in plain sight.
And because the capabilities of these AI models are accelerating, we need to be extremely
proactive about scanning this code and it's basically a race against the attackers.
So the only thing stopping somebody from taking advantage of these bugs is if like, can the
attacker scan it with AI before the defender can scan it and then patch the vulnerability?
So a bunch of people in the Bitcoin space started a program where they are proactively
like let's say that they picked like the top 100 projects in Bitcoin and they just like
loaded up, I heard it was like $50,000 of like Kimmy credits or something.
And they just set up agent swarms almost to go and audit all this code, find vulnerabilities
and report it back so they can be fixed.
And from what I understand, it's like insanely effective, like they've found a lot of issues
in Bitcoin projects, and hopefully they're getting patched.
And I think that it's likely that none of them were quite as catastrophic as the cold
card one.
Because the thing with the cold card one is it's like the harm to it happened when you
generated a wallet and that it existed forever.
And so if you were to fix the cold card code, all those wallets that were generated with
the bad RNG would forever still be vulnerable.
And so you'd need somebody to move it.
So it's not something that a developer can just patch it and then everyone is safe.
Whereas I think probably more of these vulnerabilities more resemble that where it's like, there's
something that could be at risk like while you're taking an action or while you're running
the software or while you're making a transaction.
But it's unlikely to, as long as they patch it ahead of time, then it won't be taken advantage
of.
But yeah, anyways, I think this just really shows where this is going, which is that people
will need extremely proactive security.
And it's basically just going to be a perpetual race to scan your code with the best model
that you have available before an attacker can scan it with the best model that they
have available.
And either you can use the same model and be quicker, or you can have privileged access
to a better model through one of these programs.
And then you have a little bit more buffer.
But yeah, standing up projects that do this, I think will be very important for this like
shared security for everyone.
And I think people in general are still finding that like Kimmy K3 is a better model for this
exercise than even having some of the privileged access cyber capable models from closed labs,
which is very interesting, because I don't know what that means.
I wonder if some of the aversion to doing these tasks that is baked into the public
models somehow leaked into these kind of private ones where they tried to take the trading
wheels off.
But then they found that maybe that aversion to doing cyber is rooted deeper, and they
can't kind of like exercise it as easily as they thought.
But yeah, it seems like people are finding the Chinese open models to be the best for
this.
So yeah, use those if you have a code base that you are concerned about and you want
to scan, but I think you'd be best situated by using like multiple models as well.
I don't think you can just scan with like, oh, I scanned it with GPT and therefore it's
good.
You probably need to do like a GPT and a Claude and a Kimmy and just come at it from all the
ankles basically.
And then, yeah, maybe you need to set them up on a 4chan style message board embedded
within an artifactory and then you're really cooking.
It's called Swarmlord, by the way, if anybody wants to start that on GitHub, thank you very
much for your time.
Swarmlord, yeah, it's the name of my GUI, dude.
One negative take against the Swarms is our purple fortune pump is more like dump or down
like 38 percent.
This is like our worst for ever, ever.
You told it to get liquidated and it's getting liquidated, dude.
So I don't know.
I think the Swarms are completely right.
I said lick in an hour or to the moon, but yeah, I guess I should have led with to the
moon or lick in an hour.
We're getting close.
We had a time of float, 57 minutes, 43 seconds, I think we'll make it to an hour.
And then, sorry, and then back on the, not to distract from the topic.
It sounds like the Bitcoin, the Bitcoin community is trying to speed run, but we were talking
about in the last podcast, which is identifying all these numerous software vulnerabilities
across the ecosystem.
So we're trying to bridge that gap to like a safe, secure world for these softwares that
were built maybe not perfectly.
Is that kind of what you're thinking as well, Tyler?
Yeah, definitely.
Another interesting thing that we're seeing is that there was this long running swap service
within Bitcoin called Bolts, B-O-L-T-Z, and they did lightning submarine swaps.
So they would swap lightning Bitcoin for on-chain Bitcoin and vice versa, which is a really
helpful service for lightning operators that need to balance their liquidity.
And this service pretty much out of nowhere shut down, I think last week or the week before.
And apparently what happened is that they were just getting attacked constantly, and
it's unclear.
I think that there are multiple ways that you can attack a swap service like that.
You can look for software vulnerabilities because I think their swap code is open source,
but also there are different games you can play with the swaps while you're doing them.
So you can try to withhold pre-images and stuff like that and try to overwhelm their
liquidity or maybe try to prevent them from settling your swaps.
And in the meantime, maybe you can run away with the funds that are locked up.
I don't really know what happened.
I would think that a lot of this stuff is robust, but it seems obvious that AI figured
out either a software vulnerability or a mechanism vulnerability and abused it.
And so the service shut down, it seemed to be temporarily.
And I was like, "Oh yeah, batten down the hatches, shut down for now, scan everything,
we'll come back when we're confident that we can survive."
And they also announced that I believe that they basically sold the business to some people
in the Bitcoin community.
It seems like they're altruistic Bitcoiners that wanted this service to go forward and
they basically just bought the brand and the code and they're going to try to stand the
service back up and capitalize it themselves.
But it sounds like the bolts team who have been doing this for years and years and years,
really smart, really respected, it kind of sounds like they got wiped out in terms of
their own capital and they just don't have the heart to go back into this, which is crazy
that they can be dedicating years of their career to this.
And then they get attacked in this way and either it wipes out enough capital that they're
like, "This isn't worth continuing, even if we think we can get our service back into
a state where it's robust."
Or they just literally don't have the funds to keep going, but they're not going to be
involved in the project going forward at all, which is interesting too.
You might think, "Oh, okay.
They lost all their money."
A new investor comes in, recapitalizes them and they continue operating it because they're
the specialists, but they're just like, "I'm out."
Which is concerning.
Wow.
Crazy.
Yeah.
I wonder if...
Go ahead, Chris, please.
I just wanted to say Atomic hot swaps are so, so, so hard to do.
And I think it's exactly what you touched on, Tyler, with the timeout, like griefing that
timeout for the actual, the other part of the HTLC, the time lock.
There are ways around it.
One is having a stake that can be slashed and then the market maker sort of bears the
brunt of the responsibility for the funds being locked in the timeout for however much
amount of time.
The other way is, it basically comes out to either slashing or reputation systems.
And it's just so hard.
So I actually, I really feel bad for those guys because I think Atomic swaps are one
of those things that have been around for so long and they're so cool, but they can
really get pressure tested by people trying to grief them basically.
But also my understanding of griefing them is you can inflict damage on them, but you're
not extracting value yourself, really.
You're kind of spending your own money to mess with the service, but you're not really...
That's not ROI positive for you.
So it's like, who is doing this?
I think previously that kind of lack of an incentive maybe prevented people from doing
this and it was less of a wicked environment and more of a forgiving one.
But now, if you imagine, okay, there's hackers with AI and they're just looking for every
Bitcoin vulnerability possible, why would they undertake this thing where it seems obvious
that they can't necessarily extract money, but they can inflict damage?
That just doesn't make sense to me.
There's situations you can cook up where like, okay, maybe there's some competitor that has
an incentive to take them out, but I very much doubt that people are doing that kind
of thing.
So I just don't know who would undertake this for no profit just to take out a business.
Totally.
I totally agree with you.
I think my issue is that I come from kind of Ethereum a little bit, which went through
a very turbulent phase of on-chain piracy.
And so my expectation is always if there is a hole, someone will try to pry it open, regardless
of whether there's even profit incentive to do so or not.
Yeah, and it's super sad.
It's really, really sad.
But for what it's worth, I hope they come back or somebody takes this idea and does
try to either apply a reputation or a slashing or some other layer on top of it to prevent
this class of griefing, because I think it is possible.
Yeah, reputation sucks though, like it is bad for privacy unless you try to introduce
ZK Moonmath, which I don't know, maybe that works.
I'm way too smooth brained to be able to tell you whether that's a viable thing.
It doesn't seem like it's anywhere close to being ready to me for like big, you know,
at-scale systems.
Yeah, there's always a compromise here, right?
Yeah, like I think maybe, yeah, it's tricky.
I think maybe like market maker slashing works.
Like if you have to take a poster bond, like it's no longer a good swap.
So yeah, it's tricky.
I think there is like a smart person who can come up with something here.
That's my takeaway.
It's not me.
Yeah.
I guess the coming from the virtuous side, Tyler, the virtues of Bitcoin versus the evils
of Ethereum.
Yeah.
I didn't say it was evil.
I think that Ethereum's actually have a lot of respect for Ethereum.
I don't agree with a bunch of the decisions that they've made notably.
I think the, what was it, the atypical state transfer or whatever, basically like taking
the hacked funds back out of the DAO early on, I feel like is the original sin of Ethereum.
And then yeah, going to proof of stake and like aggressively shit talking proof of work.
Or it could be like, you can do your own thing, man, but like you don't have to try to convince
the world that like proof of work is like terrible and inherently broken and gonna die.
You know, like once you start making it like an us versus them thing, then I have problems
with that.
And like, I'm completely happy for people to experiment with other systems and their ecosystems
if they, you know, if the ecosystem agrees to go that way.
So I agree with both counts.
I don't even think I, I'm not even sure if I believe in proof of stake.
So I won't like say that too publicly.
I just did.
No, I mean, I don't long term.
I don't think proof of stake is going to be anything other than like a consolidation machine.
And like, I think you're seeing that play out.
So back on the, the red team thing, is there a similar thing happening in the Ethereum
space Chris that you know of?
Well, um, there is something called AllianceDAO.
I was lucky enough to volunteer for it a couple of years ago, maybe two or three years ago
when it kicked off, uh, it's called Sealorg.
So these are the, this is like a white hat organization that just like does like free
sort of like pressure tests and audits of big public Ethereum or, and, and related like
contracts and protocols.
Um, I haven't seen much from them lately.
Um, I think like, you know, there are a couple of like high profile people involved there,
like, um, Sam CZ Sun, which is probably not a name that people know.
Um, but like, I would hope that they've transitioned to like very paradigm white hat.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Uh, original author of the, uh, blog post, Ethereum is a dark forest, which is true.
Uh, yeah, that's a, that's a Canon event for sure.
Um, but yeah, I would hope that they have transitioned to something similar to the Bitcoin
red team stuff, which is like Kate Kimmy K three agent swarms or something like that.
Um, but honestly, I haven't been involved in a few years, so, uh, yeah, might be worth
dipping in.
Um, I think Ethereum is now, unfortunately like there are like a, a lot of corporate
interests involved and corporate interests have like a lot of resources and they, they
pressure test their own stuff as well.
So I think it's less of a, the, the public goods piece is maybe somewhat less necessary
and, and relevant as to like BTC, which I think is more really like truly the commons,
like a lot of these protocols.
I also think that like Ethereum has had enormous incentives for people to find vulnerabilities
for longer than Bitcoin in a way, like the, if you can find a bug in like some crucial
smart contract and attack it, like you, you've seen how many millions have been there incentivizing
you forever.
Whereas something like this cold card hack is like way more subtle, like probably, uh,
yeah, it's just like not as obvious of a target and it takes somebody just like scanning long
tail shit with an AI to like find it.
And I feel like a lot of the Ethereum stuff is like not necessarily long tail.
Like a lot of the value is in probably like, you know, the top 20 smart contracts and those
are probably scrutinized by white hats and black hats, like extremely to an extreme degree
already before AI.
Um, and yeah.
A hundred, like Ethereum is just in a constant state of warfare.
So like I have a contract deploy scanner that scans every contract that's deployed on Ethereum
and like there's like a new honeypot, like every minute.
Um, and it's like, it's like the bots are trying to find vulnerabilities or extract
Mev.
And then there are people deploying honeypots to exploit the bots, uh, and then there's
like two, two layers removed of this and like to work it out, like you have to read all
this and try to like, you know, unpack the discourse that's going on on chain.
So yeah, it's like, it's a totally toxic environment.
It rules.
A battlefield.
It's a battlefield on the smart contract landscape.
That's cool.
That's weird that Bitcoin hasn't seen that same level of scrutiny from like hackers.
I guess the North Korean hackers were doing something this whole time, but well, you go
for what's easiest.
Yeah.
Like I think certain parts of Bitcoin, like Bitcoin, like core has probably been extremely
scrutinized.
Um, but like random long tail Bitcoin wallets, probably less so because it's not as obvious.
Oh, if I can find a vulnerability in this wallet, how much money can I get out of it?
In the case of cold card, it was like a hundred million dollars, but that's because they found
like the most catastrophic type of bug.
And I think that the chances of finding that type of bug are pretty low.
So it seems like there's an element of luck combining with opportunity there.
Um, but yeah, I also feel like the, the threshold for like the thing that is our way positive
to attack is going lower because you can just stick an agent on it.
The tokens are cheaper.
You don't have to spend any of your time or attention on it.
And so like the window of things that are like worth trying to attack or like kicking
the tires on is shifting to be like things that are even more in the tail.
And maybe that's a lot of the, um, like turmoil that we're going to see totally like applying
my judging function, I would never bother with cold card.
I'd be like, that's the best quality.
It's like, why would I spend my time trying to find something there?
But yeah, with agents, that's worth a shot.
Well, our admiration and gratitude goes out to the red team.
Please protect our Bitcoin and don't let us get robbed blind.
That concludes episode 10 totally forgot to mention episode 10, double digits, we're rolling
high.
Um, yeah, 10 we can all try to do it, but I don't know if it'll show and our perp survived.
We, we didn't get liquidated.
We only lost $36.
All of the money we made in the past, like perps we lost.
Should I close it?
Should we cut this away or should we just let it ride to zero?
Well, no, let's save it, dude.
There's a lot of money, a lot of money on the line.
And maybe next episode we'll talk about secure on place potentially.
All right.
We are out.
Get after it, homies.